Guide to the Peter Safar Papers, 1950-2003 UA.90.F102
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, I.
  - Professional Contacts, 3.
    - Kempen, Paul, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Kempen, Paul, 1988-1998 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Kerr, Mary, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Keshavan, Matcheri S., 1985-1994 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Keszler, Hugo, 1983-1994 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Kim, Seung- Ho, 1994-2000 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kirimli, Bulent, 1979-2002 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Klain, Miroslav, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Klain, Miroslav, 1981-2003 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Klain, Miroslav - Negovsky's Birthday, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Klein, Edwin, 1986-2002 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Klein, Rodger L., 2000 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Knickerbocker, Guy, 1972-2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Koerner, Henry, 1979-1996 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Kofke, W. Andrew, 1975-2002 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Kohler, Fritz, 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Koop, C. Everett, 1981-1998 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Kouwenhoven, W.B., 1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Kreimeier, Uwe, 1993-2000 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Kuboyama, Kazutoshi, 1989-2000 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Kucher, Stephanie, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Kuhnigk, Herbert, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Kuller, Lewis Henry, 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Kunkel, Herbert A., 1991-2001 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Kunkel, Richard F., 1991-2001 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Laggner, Anton, 1991-1997 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Lamont, Austin, 1997-2003 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Lane, John, 1984-1991 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Lane, John, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Lane, John, 1997-2004 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Lawin, Peter, 1971-2002 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Lee Foon, Wilfred, 1984-2003 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Lee, Kang Hyun, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Lei, Baiping, 1997-2001 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Leonov, Yuval, 1988-2001 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Lev, Lewis, 1998-2001 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Lewis, Jessica (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Levitt, Pat R., 1999 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Li, Zonghao, 1988-1998 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Lind, Bjorn, 1952-2002 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Linder, Karl, 1989-2002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Litwak, Philip, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Longnecker, David E., 19997-2002 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Lown, Bernard, 1999-2002 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Lunsford, Dade, 1989-2000 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Machado, Calixto, 1996-2001 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Macleod, Gordon, 1986-2000 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - McWilliams, Linda, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Maheshwari, Radha K., 1997 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Maling, Diana, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Marcy, Joseph, 1997-2000 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Maroon, Joseph, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Marquez, Jose, 1985-1998 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Massucci, Jamie (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Mauritz, Walkter, 1992-2001 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Maxwell, Ned, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Mayrohofer, Otto, 1983-2003 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - McGoldrick, Kathryn, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - McKenzie, Raymond, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Medearis, Don, 1998-2003 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Messmer, Konrad, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Meyer, Manfred, 1973-1983 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Meyer, Manfred, 1984-2001 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Meyers, Jack, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Milai, Samuel, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Miller, Brian, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Miller, Bruce, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Mohr, Chuck, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Monheim, Leonard, 1994-2001 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Montgomery, William, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Moosy, John, 1997-2002 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Morikawa, Sadao, 1980-1998 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Morioka, Tohru, 1985-2002 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Moroz, Victor, 1998-2000 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Moroz, Victor, 2000-2002 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Mosesso, Vince N., 1999-2002 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Motoyama, Esturo, 1973-2001 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Muller, Arnold, 1977-1994 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Mullie, Arsene, 1979-1999 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Mullner, Marcus, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Musgrave Lectures, Pittsburgh, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Naef-Frey, Hanspeter, 1983-1995 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Nagel, Eugene, 1973-2003 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Narayan, Raj K., 1993 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Negovsky, Vladimir - Pittsburgh-Moscow Connection, 1989-1993 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Negovsky, Vladimir - Pittsburgh-Moscow Connection, 1993-1999 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Negovsky,Vladimir - Paper for Resuscitation, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Negovsky, Vladimir - Birthday Celebrations, 1998-2003 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Negovsky, Vladimir - "Father of Reanimatology", 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Negovsky, Vladimir, 1986-1990 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Negovsky, Vladimir, 1991-1996 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Negovsky, Vladimir, 1997-2002 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Neumar, Robert W., 1991-1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Nehnevajsa, Jiri, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Nemoto, Edwin, 1979-2003 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Newman, Mark, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Newman, Mary, 1990-2000 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Nightengale, Chris, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Nightengale, Chris, 2000-2002 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Norlander, Olaf, 1975-1988 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Novelli, Gian-Paolo, 1995-2001 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Nunn, John F., 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Obrist, Walter, 1984-2001 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Ochi, Genro, 1995-2001 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - O'Connor, J. Dennis, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Oishi, Kazuo, 1988-1995 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Oku, Kenichi, 1988-1995 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Ore, Doris, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Orebaugh, Steven, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Ornato, Joseph, 1998-2001 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Otto, Wilbur, 1981-1990 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Palmer, Alan, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Paradis, Norman A., 1993-1996 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Paris, Paul, 1986-2002 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Patel, Rita, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Patrickson, Clive, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Peitzman, Andrew, 1989-2000 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Pena, Carlos, 1993-1995 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Pepe, Paul E., 1994-1998 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Phillips, Otto C. (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Pigula, Frank, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Pinsky, Michael, 1985-2002 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Platt, Charles, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Pokorny, Jiri, 1964-1990 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Pokorny, Jiri, 1990-2001 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Pokorny, Jiri, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Pollack, Gerald H., 2002 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Pollack, Ian F., 2000 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Pomeranz, Shlomo, 1989-1998 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Porter, Robert, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Power, David, 1980-2002 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Pozen, Michael, 1981-1984 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Pretto, Ernesto, 1987-1993 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Pretto, Ernesto, 1993-2000 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Pretto, Ernesto, 2000-2003 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Proctor, Donald, 1970-2003 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Proctor, Kenneth, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Prough, Donald, 1999-2000 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Quinlan, Joseph, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Radovsky, Ann, 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Radovsky, Ann, 1990-1992 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Radovsky, Ann, 1993-2002 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Radovsky, Ann - Rats Histology, 1984-1993 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Rao, Gutti, 1987-1992 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Sheleg, Sergey, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Sheth, Dipak, 1993-1997 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Shoemaker, William, 1972-1998 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Siegel, John H., 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Siesio, Bo, 1976-1997 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Siesio, Bo, 1997-2002 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Siker, E.S., 1992-2002 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Silverstein, Martin, 1986-1996 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Sim, Kah-Ming, 1989-1995 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Simmons, Richard L., 1987-1996 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Simon, Roger P., 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Singer, Grete, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Smith, R. Brian, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Smith, Constance, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Smith, Jan, 1994-2002 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Snyder, Cathy, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Snyder, James, 1979-2000 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Snyder, James, 2000-2003 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Sokhin, Alexander A., 1993 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sotosky, Michael, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Spaulding, Seth, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Sperling, Mark A., 1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Spivey, William H., 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Spizzirri, Carol, 2001-2002 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Srikameswarn, Anita, 2001-2002 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Stark, Nathan, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Starzl, Thomas E., 1987-2002 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Steen, Peter Andreas, 1983-1986 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Steichen, Felicien, 1982-2003 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Steinbereither, Karl, 1970-2001 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Stephenson, Hugh, 1992-2002 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Stewart, Eric, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Stewart, Ronald, 1982-1996 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Stezoski, Brad, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Stolz, Gretchen, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Stremple, John, 1989-1998 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Stremple, Paul, 1984-1988 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Sutton, Kim, 1986-1994 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Vandam, Leroy D, 1969-2001 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Vanevsky, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Ventkataraman, Ramesh, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Von Lubitz, Dag, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Vukmir, Rade B., 2004-2005 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Wachtlova, Milena, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Wachtlova, Milena, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Waldvogel, H.H., 1999 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Walgreen, Douglas, 1994-1997 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Yuanfan, Wang, 1991-2002 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Wanzer, Sidney, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Warner, David S., 1996-2003 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Watkins, W. David, 1992-2001 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Watoh, Yukihiro, 1990-1997 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Watson, Charles, 1987-2000 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Wecht, Cyril, 1996-2003 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Weichinger, Ridolf, 1999-2003 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Weil, Max Harry, 1979-1990 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Weil, Max Harry, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Weil, Max Harry, 1993-1999 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Weil, Max Harry, 2000-2002 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Weil, Max Harry - Grant Application, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Weil, Max Harry - Acid Base Grant, 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Weinrauch, Victor, 1990-1998 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Weise, Craig A., 1968 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Werkgartner, Fritz, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Werkgartner, Georg, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Werner, Georg, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Werner, Joyce Z., 1981-1985 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - White, Blaine C., 1982-1991 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Wolfson, Sidney K., 1976-1992 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Wu, Hsiao-hsing, 1979-1998 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Wu, Shi-Jei, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Wuerth, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Xiao, Feng, 1991-1995 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Xiao, Feng, 1996-2005 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Xu, Yan, 1993-2002 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Yakulis, Robert, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Yang, Chen-Ping, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Yang, Zhen-Min, 1981-2001 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Yao, Shanglong, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Yealy, Donald M. (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Zang, Yang, Liu, 1980-1984 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Zang, Yang, Liu, 1985-2001 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Zar, Harvey, 1989-1993 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Zar, Harvey, 1994-1996 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Zeidel, Mark, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Zelman, Vladimir, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Zhang, Jing Fan, 1982-1992 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Zimpfer, Michael, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Zindler, Martin, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Zsingmond, Elemer K., 1975 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Zuegg, Florian, 1982-1988 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Zulch, Klaus J., 1976-1978 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - General Correspondence, 4.
    This subseries includes correspondence between Peter Safar and various colleagues. The records are arranged by personal, professional, and foreign correspondence and then chronologically. Some folders contain material that is restricted and in languages other than English.
    - Foreign Personal Correspondence, 1979-1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1971-1982 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Personal Correspondence Forms and Certificates, 1976-1987 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1979-1985 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Professional Correspondence, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Professional Correspondence, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Professional Correspondence, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Professional Correspondence, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence by Topic, 5.
    This subseries includes correspondence which Peter Safar had arranged by topic. Some folders contain restricted material.
    - Brain Resuscitation, 1979-1987 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Cardiopulmonary Cerebral Resuscitation Case Registry, 1982-1987 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - CPR Cases, 1979-1986 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - CPR Correspondence, 1982-1993 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Lawyers, 1982-1992 (Box 17, Folder 27)
- Conferences and Meetings, II.
  This series contains files regarding meetings and conferences attended by Safar, some of which he helped to organize or served as a speaker. Included are correspondence, programs and pamphlets for these conferences.
  - American Medical Association, Conference on Categorization of Emergency Medical Facilities, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Wolf Creek Conference I, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Symposium Announcements, Invitations, Brochures, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Brazil Meeting, 1975-1978 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
  - Poland Conferences, 1975-1982 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Vienna Critical Care Medicine Lecture, 1977-1979 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Israeli Conferences and Correspondence, 1977-1987 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Annual American Society of Anesthesiologists Meeting, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Israel Society of Anesthesiologists, 11th Congress Abstracts and Thank You's, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Innsburck Congress, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Pan-American Congress on Critical Care Medicine, Mexico City, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Society of Critical Care Medicine Symposium, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Critical Care Medicine, 17th Annual Symposium, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - First International Conference on First Aid at the Scene of an Accident, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Western Pennsylvania Heart Association and Jaycees Award, 1978-1981 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - 2nd International Congress on Disaster Management, Jerusalem, 1978-1990 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Annual American Society of Anesthesiologists Meeting, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Blood Substitutes and Research, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Wolf Creek Conference II, 1979-1981 (Box 18, Folder 20-23)
  - American Heart Association, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Collaborative Randomized Clinical Study of Cardiopulmonary-Cerebral Resuscitation, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - CPR Self Training Paper, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Princeton Conference, Williamsburg, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Potsdam Symposium, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - World Federation of Societies of Anesthesiologists, Hamburg Meeting, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - 18th Bernard H. Eliasberg Symposium, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Meeting/Conferences Invitations and Programs, 1981-1985 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Wolf Creek Conference III, 1981-1987 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Israel-Related News, 1982-1991 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Annual American Society of Anesthesiologists Meeting, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - 5th Purdue Conference on CPR and Defibrillation, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Asia Visit, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 9-11)
  - Asia Visit Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - 12th General Meeting of Japanese Association for Acute Medicine, Recent Advances in Cardiopulmonary-Cerebral Resuscitation, Hiroshima Lecture, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - 6th Purdue Conference on CPR and Defibrillation, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Meeting of Academy of Natural Sciences, East Germany, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 15-17)
  - Annual American Society of Anesthesiologists Meeting, Las Vegas, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Ludwig Boltzmann Symposium on CPCR, Austria, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Meeting/Conferences Invitations and Programs, 1986-1997 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - 14th Annual Seminar in Pulmonary Physiology and Medicine, Pittsburgh, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Wolf Creek Conference IV, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - 10th World Congress on Emergency and Disaster Medicine, 1992-1997 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Grand Rounds, Department of Anesthesiology/Critical Care Medicine, John Hopkins, 1994-2000 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Society of Critical Care Medicine and American College of Critical Care Medicine, 1995-1996 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - 10th World Congress on Disaster and Emergency Medicine, Germany, 1995-1997 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 13th Annual Merel H. Harmel Lectureship, Duke University, 1996-2000 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Doctor Honoris Causa Lecture, Germany, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
  - Public Safety Radio Interviews, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - ABC News Interview, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - 35th Annual Meeting of the Society for Cryobiology, Pittsburgh, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Colegio de Medicos y Cirujanos (College of Doctors and Surgeons) Honorary Awards, Costa Rica, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Suspended Animation Clinical Investigators Meeting, Pittsburgh, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - BBC Hypothermia and Reanimation TV Program Correspondence, 1998-200 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - 5th Annual Symposium on the Applied Physiology of Peripheral Circulation, Pittsburgh, 1998-2002 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Vienna, 1998-2002 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - 11th World Congress on Disaster and Emergency Medicine Japan, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - 40th Anniversary of CPR Symposium, Baltimore, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 16-23)
  - American Heart Association Meeting, New Orleans, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - American Society of Anesthesiologists Annual Meeting, San Francisco, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Cerebral Blood Flow Chapter, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Lewis H. Wright Memorial Lecture, San Francisco, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 2-5)
  - St. Francis Medical Center, Visiting Professorship, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - CPR Venelation Related Papers/Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - CPR Ventilation Related Papers/Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Learning Channel Interview, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - World Congress on Drowning, Amsterdam, 2000-2003 (Box 21, Folder 10-15)
  - 31st Critical Care Congress, Society of Critical Care Medicine, San Diego, 2000-2002 (Box 21, Folder 16-17)
  - 15th International Trauma Anesthesia and Critical Care Society, Stavanger, 2000-2002 (Box 21, Folder 18-20)
  - Ralf Walters Celebration, Madison, 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - 1st Ohio Emergency Cardiac Care Conference, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 54th Annual American Academy of Neurology, Denver, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 2-5)
  - Advanced Technology Applications for Combat Casualty Care, St. Pete Beach, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - American Society of Anesthesiologists Annual Meeting, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - American Heart Association and Emergency Cardiac Care Conference, Dallas, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
  - European Resuscitation Council, Florence, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Neurocritical Care Symposium, Cleveland, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Society of Critical Care Medicine, San Antonio, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - International Brain Hypothermia Symposium, Tokyo, 2002-2004 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - 26th Annual Conference on Shock, Phoenix, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - American Society of Anesthesiologists Meeting, San Francisco, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Anesthesiology Grand Rounds, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Association of University Anesthesiologists, Milwaukee, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Critical Care Medicine Grand Rounds, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Meeting and Conference Invitations and Correspondence, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Wolf Creek Conference VII, Palm Springs, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 20)
- Professional Organizations and Committees, III.
  This series contains information about Peter Safar's participation in a variety of organizations and committees. Much of this work is concerned with his efforts nationally to create emergency medical services (EMS) bills and the standardization of emergency care.
  - Advisory Board, Beekman's Downtown Hospitals, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - American Heart Association Film, EKG in Emergency Vehicles, 1969-1972 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - American Heart Association on Emergency Medical Services, General Correspondence, 1961-1971 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Emergency and Critical Care Medicine International, 1967-1976 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Emergency and Critical Care Medicine National, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - EMS Bill, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - EMS Bill 504, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - EMS Interagency Committee, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 28-29)
  - EMS Interagency Committee, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - EMS Interagency Committee, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - EMS Interagency Committee (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - EMS National, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - EMS National, 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - EMS Politics, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Emergency Medical Service Act, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Inspection and Evaluation Procedures for Medical Equipment in Ambulances (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - National Research Council, Committee on Emergency Medical Services, 1967-1969 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - National Research Council, Committee on Emergency Medical Services, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - National Research Council, Committee on Emergency Medical Services, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - National Research Council, Committee on Emergency Medical Services, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - National Research Council, Committee on Emergency Medical Services, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - National Research Council, Committee on Emergency Medical Services, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Roster of Members and Authority Structure Functions: Public Advisory Committees, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 16)
- Publications, IV.
  This series contains copies of many of Peter Safar's publications. These include journal articles, manuals and also research completed by Safar.
  - Journal Articles, 1.